LIMAN ADAMU LABARAN

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Email: glimanadamu@gmail.com

Cell: +1 416 882 9896

Address: 1926 Lake Shore Blvd. West, Toronto, Ontario,

Canada

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u>

PROFILE

With over 8+ years of experience. As a Senior Software Developer at Hellofresh, he has been involved in building microservices and data pipelines. Leading initiatives that have improved the conversion top line by 20% with a revenue impact of 10% geographically. He is well versed in distributed systems, full stack developments and has worked in domains such as Mobility and Finance in the past.

He mentors software engineers on building microservices using event-based approach during his free time. Also, he engages in Hackathons when he gets some time to showcase his strengths.

SKILLS

Coding Languages

Python, JavaScript, Golang

Frameworks/Systems

Flask, FastAPI, AIOHttp, Django, React, Vue, AWS services, Laravel, GraphQL, Express, NodeJS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Databases(MySQL, PostgreSQL & MongoDB), Redis, Firebase, Salesforce, ETLs with PySpark, AirFlow, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Grafana

Others

Testing, TDD & DDD, Terraform, Git, Agile (Scrum & Kanban)

EDUCATIONAL TRAINING

<u>Kwame Nkrumah University of Science & Technology</u>

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Attended from Sept. 2007 to June 2011
- · Facilitator, School of Groups Coding Club
- Lead Developer, Vacation Bootcamps

CAREER SUMMARY

Senior Software Developer

<u>Hellofresh</u> | April 2021 to present Toronto, Canada

 Developing backend features to expand tax collections from 1m+ orders in a day across additional business units which reduces the pay from pocket of taxes.

Software Developer

<u>Door2Door</u> | November 2019 to March 2021 Berlin, Germany

 I worked with the mobility intelligence team to build a tool for planning, running and optimizing a multimodal transport system for major cities including Berlin, Munich and Münster. This provided various options for thousands of residents of those cities to move about with a minimum cost.

Senior Full Stack Developer

 $\underline{\text{Comfort Works}} \mid \text{December 2018 to Nov. 2019} \\ \text{Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia}$

 Developed backend (ecommerce checkout, payment and order management) and frontend (user interactions)

Lead & Senior Software Developer

<u>Callens Solutions Ltd.</u> | August 2017 to Nov. 2018 Accra, Ghana

- Conducted interviews, hire, train and mentor new software developers
- Led in designing, development and implementation of ecommerce and CRM systems

Software Engineer

<u>Hubtel</u> | June 2016 to April 2017 Accra, Ghana

• Designed, developed and enhanced a number of industry-leading technology solutions

Consultant & Software Engineer

<u>Grameen Foundation</u> | June 2014 to May 2016 Accra, Ghana

- Developed the MOTECH platform and it's APIs
- Designed and developed web and mobile applications for the Noyawa Project

Software Engineer

<u>Corenett Limited</u> | October 2012 to June 2014 Accra, Ghana

- Developed USSD, Java and HTML5 Web Apps
- Application Server Administration, Kannel(SMS)
 Server Management & Configurations